Sewall Wright Papers 1895-1988 Mss.Ms.Coll.60
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Biographical and autobiographical materials, 1897-1980; 0.5 Linear feet (Box Series III-1)
  - Plan-Schedule [Sewall Wright], n.d. (Box Series III-1)
  - Supplementary Statement, 1949 (Box Series III-1)
    Paperwork completed for year at Edinburgh
  - Summary of Career--Sewall Wright, 1976; 2 folders (Box Series III-1)
  - Travel log [Sewall Wright], 1949 (Box Series III-1)
  - Wonders of Nature, 1897 (Box Series III-1)
    Boyhood book by Sewall Wright
  - Wolff, George Louis, 1972 (Box Series III-1)
    Curriculum vita
- Series IIIa. Transcripts of oral history interviews, 1969-1980; 0.75 Linear feet (Box Series IIIa-1-2)
  Fifty eight folders of interview transcripts, prepared from 52 tape recordings made by William Provine during research for his book, Sewall Wright and Evolutionary Biology.
  Biographical and personal data -- Wright, Sewall; Castle, William Ernest; Evolution; Fisher, Ronald Aylmer; Genetics; Harvard University; History of biology, especially genetics; Physiology; Population genetics; Rat genetics; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
  - Transcripts Sides 1-3, Spring 1969 (Box Series IIIa-1)
    Mss corrections
  - Transcripts Sides 1-3, Spring 1969 (Box Series IIIa-1)
    Typed corrections
    Fisher on dominance, pp. 12-18
    Fisher on random drift, pp. 20-21
    Samplings and other kinds of drift, pp. 21-26
  - Transcripts Part I, March 1, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
  - Transcripts Part II, March 1, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
  - Transcripts Parts I and II, March 1, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
    Selective diffusion and mass selection, p.8
    1925 paper, pp. 9-10
    Meets Fisher, p.9, and part II, p. 6
    Fisher on dominance, pp. 11-13 and part II, p. 8-10
    Plunkeet on dominance, p. 14
    1925 paper-dropped out selection, part II, p.5
    Sends 1925 paper to Fisher, part II, p. 7
    Level to which Wright's theory of evolution was directed, part II, p. 16
  - Transcripts Part III, [March] 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
  - Transcripts Part III, [March] 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
  - Transcripts Part IV, March 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
  - Transcripts Part IV, March 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
  - Transcripts Part V, March 2, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
  - Transcripts Part V, March 2, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
    Fisher on dominance, p. 8
    1925 paper, p. 11
  - Transcripts Part VI, [March 1976] (Box Series IIIa-1)
  - Transcripts Part VI, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
    Castle, selection experiments on rats, p. 3-6
    MacDowell, Castle and size inheritance, p. 6
  - Transcripts Part VII, Sides 1 and 2, March 2, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
  - Transcripts Part VII, Sides 1 and 2, March 2, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
    Harvard Teachers, pp. 5-6
    Jeffrey, [Wheeler]
    [Sumner and Wirt], pp. 9-10
  - Transcripts Part IX, March 2, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
  - Transcripts Part IX and X, March 2, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
    Castle on mutable genes, part X, p. 1
  - Transcripts Part XI, sides 1 and 2, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
    Wright's disapproval of random drift as source of non-adaptive characteristics in species, pp. 1-3.
    An excellent discussion of the 1932 paper and Wright's emphasis upon random drift
    Very useful for Wright's modern view of the role played by random drift
  - Transcripts Part XII, sides 1 and 2, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
  - Transcripts Part XIII, sides 1 and 2, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-1)
    Confusions of the 1932 paper; excellent and very useful discussion
  - Transcripts Part I and II, June 4, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Part I and II, June 4, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-2)
    Fisher, p. 2
    Fisher and dominance, pp. 3-9
    My (William Provine's) inference about break-up after [Wright's] Review of genetical theory of natural selection, op. 6 [very important]
  - Transcripts November 23, 1976 (Box Series IIIa-2)
    2 copies; Mss and typed corrections
    Shifting balance, p.7
  - Transcripts Side 1, May 17, 1978 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Side 2, May 17, 1978 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Sides 1 and 2, May 17, 1978 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Part III, May 18, 1978 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Part III and IV, May 18, 1978 (Box Series IIIa-2)
    Genesis of Wright's evolutionary theory
    Changes between 1925 6t 1932 papers, part II, p. 5
    Wright x Fisher--corrections back and forth, 1929-30, part II, pp. 8-9
  - Transcripts Part IV, May 18, 1978 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Part V, May 18, 1978 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Part I, tape 15 side 2, 1978 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 1, side B, September 11, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 2, part A, September 11, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
    Mss corrections, not in SW's handwriting
  - Transcripts Tape 3, sides A and B, September 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 4, sides A and B, September 12, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 5, sides A and B, September 12, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 6, sides A and B, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
    Very imp. tape on evolutionary theory, evolution of dominance, interaction with Fisher, 1931 and 1932 papers, etc.
  - Transcripts Tape 7, side A, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 8, side A, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
    Very important discussion of the papers after 1932 and comparisons with 1931 and 1932 papers. Especially 1937 PNAS paper. Says clearly that the 1931 paper was not up to his qualitative theory (p.6). Good discussion of part III of 1931 paper
  - Transcripts Tape 9, sides A and B, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 10, sides A, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 11, sides A and B, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 12, sides A, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 13, sides A and B, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 14, sides A and B, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 15, sides A and B, 1979 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcript sides 1-4, February 9, 1980 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcript Part I, sides 1 and 2, June 2, 1980 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcript Part II, sides 1 and 2, June 2, 1980 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcript Part III, sides 1 and 2, June 2, 1980 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcript Part IV, sides 1 and 2, June 2, 1980 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcript Part V, sides 1 and 2, June 2, 1980 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcript Part VI, sides 1 and 2, June 2, 1980 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcript Part VII, sides 1 and 2, June 4, 1980 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcripts Tape 8, sides 1 and 2, 1980 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcript Part IX, sides 1 and 2, June 5, 1980 (Box Series IIIa-2)
  - Transcript Part X, sides A only, 1980 (Box Series IIIa-2)
- Series IV. Photographs, 0.5 Linear feet (Box Series IV-1)
  Images of Wright, his family, and his colleagues. For the images used by William Provine in Sewall Wright and evolutionary biology, Provine's captions have been transcribed on the front of the folders. Charts and diagrams used in Provine's book are also included in this series.
  Folders are arranged alphabetically by the subject of the photograph.
  - Adaptive landscape (Folder Series IV-1)
    Provine Figure 9.1
  - Castle's geometric representation of gametes (Folder Series IV-2)
    Provine Figure 2.4
  - William Ernest Castle, 1917 (Folder Series IV-3)
    Provine Figure 2.1
  - Color series (Folder Series IV-4)
    Provine Figure 3.5
  - The Committee (Folder Series IV-5)
  - Constants used in calculations of the additive properties of covariances" (Folder Series IV-6)
    Provine Figure 5.3. Results of Wright's "Purely algebraic proof
  - Correlations between bone measurements (Folder Series IV-7)
    Provine Figure 5.1
  - Diagram illustrating the causal relations between litter mates (0,0') each of them and their parents (Folder Series IV-8)
    Provine Figure 5.5
  - A diagram illustrating the system of interactions between corn crop...breeding.") (Folder Series IV-9)
    Provine 5.9 (From Provine chapter, "Path coefficients and animal
  - Dilution effects (Folder Series IV-10)
    Provine Figure 4.5
  - The dilution series (Folder Series IV-11)
    Provine Figure 3.4
  - Edward Murray East (Folder Series IV-12)
    Provine Figure 2.2
  - Field of gene combinations occupied by a population within the general field of possible combinations (Folder Series IV-13)
    Provine Figure 9.2
  - Figures 4.3a and b (Folder Series IV-14)
    Contents missing
  - General formulae for inbreeding (Folder Series IV-15)
    Provine Figure 5.7
  - Grades of otocephalyand throat of the 12 grades in comparison with the normal (O)." (Folder Series IV-16)
    Provine Figure 4.7. "Semidiagrammatic ventral views of the head
  - Heredity and the environment (Folder Series IV-17)
    Provine Figure 5.6
  - Hypothetical process involved in melanin pigment production and points of action of factors as deduced from the effects of factor combinations (Folder Series IV-18)
    Provine Figure 4.6
  - Path diagramand Animal Breeding.") (Folder Series IV-19)
    Provine Figure 5.8. (From Provine Chapter, "Path Coefficients
  - Relative importance of different classes of size factors of five bone lengths (Folder Series IV-20)
    Provine Figure 5.2
  - Response curve, redrawn form Fisher's letter (Folder Series IV-21)
    Provine Figure 8.1
  - Table 1: Results of crossing the plus selected race with a wild race; Table 2: Results of crossing the minus selected race with a wild race (Folder Series IV-22)
    Provine Figure 3.1
  - Subdivision of a breed into small groups which exchange breeding stock only at race intervals and then only with neighboring local groups (Folder Series IV-23)
    Provine Figure 9.3
  - Summary of correlations [between one skeletal dimension and another] (Folder Series IV-24)
    Provine Figure 3.2
  - Two-dimensional fitness surface, redrawn from Wright's letter (Folder Series IV-25)
    Provine 8.2
  - University of Chicago, group photograph, Zoology, 1937 (Folder Series IV-26)
    Identification sheet, no photograph
  - Unidentified photo (Folder Series IV-27)
    Sewall Wright, 1909/10?
  - Unidentified photo (Folder Series IV-28)
  - Unidentified group photo (Folder Series IV-29)
    Extended Wright family?
  - Unidentified girl (Folder Series IV-30)
  - Unidentified girl (Folder Series IV-31)
  - Unidentified girl (Louise Wright?) (Folder Series IV-32)
  - Elizabeth Quincy Sewall Wright (Folder Series IV-33)
    Provine Figure 1.2
  - Elizur Wright (Folder Series IV-34)
  - Elizur Wright III and Susan Clark Wright (Folder Series IV-35)
  - Wright Family I (Folder Series IV-36)
  - Wright Family II (Folder Series IV-37)
  - Sewall Wright holding a guinea pig in each hand, c. 1920 (Folder Series IV-38)
    Provine Figure 4.8
  - Louise Wright soon after marriage to Sewall Wright (Folder Series IV-39)
    Provine Figure 4.2
  - [Louise Wright] (Folder Series IV-40)
  - Louise Wright -- Wedding photo (Folder Series IV-41)
  - Philip Green Wright (Folder Series IV-42)
  - Quincy Wright (Folder Series IV-43)
    Provine Figure 1.3
  - Sewall Wright, 1928 (Folder Series IV-44)
  - Sewall Wright, 1930 (Folder Series IV-45)
  - [Sewall Wright] (Folder Series IV-46)
  - Sewall Wright portrait (Folder Series IV-47)
  - Sewall Wright (Folder Series IV-48)
  - Wright, [Sewall], LeRoy and Hillock (Folder Series IV-49)
    Provine Figure 1.5. Railroad crew -- in mock defense pose
  - Sewall Wright at Cornell University, 1922 (Folder Series IV-50)
    Similar to Provine Figure 4.1
  - Sewall Wright graduation photo (Folder Series IV-51)
  - Sewall Wright in group photo (Folder Series IV-52)
  - Sewall Wright at Mishima Experimental Station, 1968 (Folder Series IV-53)
    Provine Figure 13.3
  - Sewall Wright at the 25th anniversary of the Jackson Laboratory (Folder Series IV-54)
    Provine Figure 13.2
  - Sewall Wright and Louise Wright -- Wedding photo (Folder Series IV-55)
  - Sewall Wright, Professor of Zoology, Chicago (Folder Series IV-56)
  - Sewall Wright, Railroad engineering in South Dakota (Folder Series IV-57)
    Provine Figure 1.4
  - Sewall Wright at University of Chicago, 1928 (Folder Series IV-58)
  - Ted Wright (Folder Series IV-59)